[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
boom welcome everyone to the stoa
place where we cohere in dialogue about
what matters most at the knife's edge of
this very moment i'm the stuart peter
lindbergh
and today we have the future thinkers
in the stoa uh uv
ivanova and mike gilliland
to superstars in the sense making web
and
they're going to talk about something
that they're working on a special
project
called the smart village um so i've
known
mike in uv for a while now we were part
of this secret sense making mafia
mastermind group
and then all of a sudden like they're
like hey peter we're doing a smart
village i'm like what
what what is this this this sounds
awesome uh and then they
recently released this epic video that
we're all gonna watch in a moment
um so yeah i'm really excited i don't
know much about the project
so the this is sort of like a preview
for the stova family to get an idea of
it
um so how today's gonna work is in a
moment i'm gonna take
mike in and mike is gonna share um just
a few videos
uh maybe an exclusive one on the smart
village
and i'll be asking them some questions
uh and if you're familiar with the whole
conestoga jam
write your questions down anytime in the
chat box if you
uh i'll call on you to meet yourself
during that portion
uh and then you submit yourself and then
ask your question to mike and uv
uh if you don't want to be on youtube
because this will be on youtube just
indicate that in the chat when you ask
your question
is that being said mike yuvee how's it
going
it's going good quite the intro thanks
um yeah this thing this has been a long
time coming this is about 10 years of
planning
planning visioning thinking about it and
now we're finally doing it it's funny
how kovid uh
accelerates certain things and that's
what's happened for us
it seemed like it was kind of an uphill
battle trying to get this thing off the
ground
before and then covet hit and suddenly
everybody's like wait a second i want to
live in a smart village i don't want to
be in the city this sucks
so yeah yes i didn't know that you guys
were thinking about this for
for 10 years now yeah since we first
started dating really this this is
something we've been talking about
mm-hmm yeah
is that your pickup line like i'm
onboard to a smart i was going to smart
village one day
like me too i think i think my pickup
line was i have an 88 key keyboard at
home semi waited come play it
[Laughter]
that would win
yeah um so yeah this is you know and
we've asked ourselves like we've been
traveling around for a while too we were
uh kind of doing the digital nomad thing
since 2012.
living in southeast asia living in
europe and we had originally
um we didn't have a location in mind for
where we would want to do this thing we
just thought wherever we were at the
moment
felt like the right place and so we kind
of
started a public initiative to build a
smart village in
bulgaria where we were living at the
time
and it was a challenge and then covid
hit and we had our first child
and it became clear we needed to be back
home
in canada where we're from and uh be
close to family and
you know raise our our son in more of a
community with a network we already have
with kind of a culture that we
understood and so we moved back in the
midst of covid
and then just put the idea out there to
the world
that we're going to build this center in
british columbia and then a lot of
people came out of the woodwork and
started helping
and within about a month or so in fact a
lot of those people are in this call
right now too i can see
hey guys hey tyson hi everyone
um yeah so people came out and started
helping us find properties and then we
looked at a few different properties
found this one
this one in um caslo or near caslo
um in the kootenays that is 107 acres
with a bunch of existing properties with
structures
or as structures and with solar panels
and the
it turns we had a conversation with the
owners and the owners wanted to partner
with us they listened to our podcast and
loved the vision and offered to partner
with us on this project
yeah they've been running it as a farm
since the 90s as an organic farm
and they you know saw that partnering
with us would
take it to the next level and add all
the you know technology component and
the network
and the community aspect that we want to
bring
and so yeah it's unfolded very
organically
in a very cool way just like we i
constantly feel like we're at the right
time and in the right place
doing this yeah so totally
um so i have a bunch of questions but
might be prudent to watch that that
video
um because that gives you a preview and
then we can kind of uh
jump off from there yeah let's do it
all right
and there's some exclusive content too
apparently yeah so
i have two videos here actually one i
just finished exporting right before we
started and it's a collection of all the
drone shots we took a drone out there
and
just went nuts for a couple of days with
it so we've got lots of
really cool aerial footage of the
property that nobody has seen yet
there's barely any of it in the main
intro video so
i can set up the intro video first and
then if you guys want we'll check out
the drone shots here
so can you just let me know that this is
like this is displaying properly
does it look weird and super widescreen
or how does that look uh this
should be good uh this little wide
screen okay
i can fix that or we can just go forward
um
maybe play it for a bit and see what
happens sure so many ways that city
looks there are so many ways that cities
make life unsustainable and miserable
the noise the expense overcrowding
social unrest pollution and the
separation from nature
people are isolated and stuck in these
tiny little boxes that make it
impossible to feel connected
and be healthy or even see the stars
these cities are built on an extractive
and consumptive economic model
that destroys ecosystems and is held
together with fragile supply chains
and the illusion of infinite growth we
really don't have to live this way
we could build our villages towns and
cities on the principles of biomimicry
to be resilient decentralized diverse
and attuned to the local environment but
we're going to need a testing ground
a place where new systems and ideas can
be prototyped and where old wisdom can
regain its place in modern culture
that's exactly what we're doing with the
future thinkers smart village
a place for regenerative living learning
and creating
we're mike and eubie we're the hosts of
the future thinkers podcast
a long-running show featuring guests
like daniel schmuckenberger
jordan hall ken wilbur jordan peterson
and more
we teach courses and workshops on
sovereignty resilience
sense-making and collective intelligence
practices and in nearly every one of our
episodes we ask the question
how can we adapt to the changing world
we live in
we're aiming to create a place for
living learning
creating and growing with programs that
help people
recognize their own sovereignty and
interconnectedness
we focus on regenerating the individual
the community
and the ecosystem our idea is to connect
networks of smart villages to build a
set of blueprints
practices and a knowledge base of what
works and what doesn't
we're moving on to a 107 acre off-grid
property in the heart of the kootenays
in british columbia canada
when you visit or live there you'll be
able to stay in a variety of sustainably
built homes
and over time we'll be adding more new
and experimental dwellings
if you want to get your hands dirty
there'll be lots of projects to
contribute to like facilitating events
and education programs
building new structures or working in
the garden
we also want to encourage participants
to start sustainable businesses and be
part of the local economy
if you're a content creator you can use
our multimedia studio to make videos
podcasts music design and other forms of
art
storytelling and knowledge sharing is
going to be a huge part of this village
which is why it's one of the first
things we're going to set up
we already have an electric vehicle
sharing program so if you need to get
picked up or you just want to tour
around the area you can do it
you can also take part in all kinds of
outdoor activities and adventures in the
area
the kootenais have some amazing nature
to explore and we plan to use only clean
transportation to keep it that way
over the next five years we're going to
be expanding what we do
one of our earlier projects will be to
build a maker space with cnc machines
laser cutters 3d printers and more the
idea is to have a creative playground
where many ideas can be tried and tested
if you're already a listener of the
future thinkers podcast you're going to
love the programs that we'll be hosting
including co-working and co-living stays
that are focused on developing
regenerative practices
workshops and festivals hackathons and
idea incubators
outdoor and wilderness adventures and
lots of personal development retreats
we've partnered with friends family and
the previous owners of the property and
we're looking to start building and
running events in 2021
if you're interested in visiting living
there sponsoring
partnering or investing in the project
go to futurethinkers.org
village and click the contribute button
and if you're inspired by the vision
share the project with your friends
we're really excited to bring this
project to life
together and with your help
[Music]
it's so painful watching that again i
hate my voice over
yeah so um yeah we
probably open it up to questions for a
little bit here
should you think peter yeah sure um i
have some questions so if you have any
questions start throwing them in the
chat
um i'll ask uh the questions that
someone just threw like how many how
many people will be living on site
that's a good one so because um
the idea is to have it kind of like a
lab
um we are not going to grow it very fast
in terms of how many people live there
i think we will cap it at 50 adults but
that will be over several years
to start we'll just have a couple
families living there because there are
already some existing structures that
can accommodate that but as we build
more structures and rezone parts of the
property to
fit more houses we'll increase the
capacity um one thing that's really
important for us is to make sure that
social cohesion is there
um that we all get along and that you
know we're all there
purposefully working on something um in
you know working on the project itself
or related projects that help
um grow and create the culture
um so yeah for the first little while
it'll
it'll be quite small but it'll grow over
time there's there's a point to this i
think is worth illustrating here that
wasn't quite included in the video which
is the storytelling and the
the kind of we want to build a
documentary
around this and then do more of these
types of project and
projects in the region and then around
the world yeah so we want to figure out
what works and what doesn't
document our failures and successes as
we go forward
get a series of of either a web episode
or some sort of netflix
series going and um so that's why i put
so much effort into the the initial
video and the
the selling of this idea out there
because
i think that's going to play a big role
in inspiring people that want to do this
thing themselves to start more of these
villages yeah
and the idea is not to uh create this as
like
this is the ultimate thing more like
this is a testing ground
and here's what works for us here's what
here's what worked and here's what
didn't and
uh people everywhere in the world can
apply these same principles to start
villages of their own rather than having
like this is the ultimate retreat center
that you can
you know come to uh yeah
right so you're leading the way uh and
by example and as an experiment and a
test to see what works
um and hopefully inspire other people um
have you taken
inspiration from any existing kind of
intentional communities
uh current or prior um individuals
we're paying a lot of attention to we
started a regenerative
smart village series on the podcast
and we've interviewed a number of people
who are doing really interesting
projects of their own
not exactly the same model but some
similar crossover elements
i would say that we've also taken
negative inspiration
from existing eco villages like on what
not to do
and this is where we saw an opportunity
to do something different
yeah i've the feeling that i get looking
at it
we don't we haven't been to a lot of
different smart villages but the feeling
i get generally from our research
is that there are a lot of people kind
of escaping
um either technology or society
or the impending apocalypse
like any number of things people there
seems to be this escapist attitude and
that's not what we want to do
we want to figure out ways to template a
different way of living
and also some sort of new culture
uh because that's going to be kind of
the founding seed that everything else
blossoms from
so culture is a and the ability to be in
relation
which is essentially what you guys are
doing here in in the stoa like
that's going to be a very critical part
of this
and what is the sort of the sourcing
application onboarding process like for
people who want to live in this smart
village
well we're working through a lot of the
details i mean there are so
many so many moving parts we don't only
been back in canada since march so
there's like
there's a lot to figure out we don't
exactly know what the onboarding process
is and
i don't think there's an easy way
to figure out how well we're going to
gel with people
and how well how much people can
contribute until they're actually on the
property
staying there for a short term period of
time and and
working how they they can contribute so
it's been an emergent process and
learning process so
that's one of the things that we're
pretty transparent about is that we
don't know how to do this
we're figuring it out as we go and i
think that's really exciting
and like we're kind of approaching it as
a startup you know yeah
startup mentality like it's okay to fail
and we know that you know we'll figure
out a lot of things as we go
so yeah but as far as people coming on i
i think
we're gonna try and expand one of the
first projects we're gonna do is to
make a bit of an rv park so that we can
have more people coming on so we can
have higher
uh levels of accommodation and then
people can test it out and then there
are
more structures and there'll be more
spots for more permanent dwellings over
time
but for the first little while we're
focusing on people who are
um entrepreneurial to you know in order
to build a culture and build out the the
community
and and kind of inject a lot of ideas
but also the ability to execute on those
ideas
yeah for that documentary i think that's
a brilliant
kind of like artistic experiment to have
along with this project
are you going to release it in segments
you're going to release like a whole big
one
well generally when you're pitching to
netflix or any of these kind of bigger
stations you need a pilot you probably
want a couple of episodes
and then you pitch that idea ongoing for
a period of time until you get picked up
and funded to do a whole season
so i love the idea of focusing on a web
series
and just having no finite end
to that and then as we collect as we
make more episodes then just be pitching
all along
yeah and mike's background is in in film
and audio
so he's got connections to a lot of
people working in the industry so
yeah super cool
you had a question on governance
if you're gonna unmute yourself
where is he here ryan campbell
okay i'll read it on his behalf then um
what will governance or decision-making
hierarchies look like do you have
protocols or software to help
facilitate a social cohesion cohesion
yeah that is something we've been
developing a good amount of experience
with with our group calls in the last
couple of years
um and we're very we're kind of
sticklers for
minimum minimum hierarchy and minimum
rules
and a lot of the time in those group
calls people will call for more rules
but
we resist that like let's figure out how
to build our interpersonal
uh conflict resolution abilities so that
we don't have to account with a rule set
for every possible
disagreement or problem let's just
figure out how to get good at
being in disagreement and resolving it
yeah so
i i intend and so the short answer is no
we don't have a lot of
kind of governance structures we have
uh right now the way things are set up
is that there's a company that will own
the land
and so the actual hard assets and a
degree of the voting rights will be
represented through
certain types of shares in the company
which different people will um yeah so
we don't exactly have that
perfectly laid out but there will be
different shares that represent decision
making and you might not care about the
decision making of every aspect of the
the village you might have a specific
areas
of expertise so we're hoping to
represent that
and because we're starting with a small
number of people
the uh the governance structure of just
like we sit in a circle and we talk it
out until we arrive at a conclusion
and until we're on the same page that
i think it'll be sufficient for the
first while as the village grows and as
there are more decision makers and more
different projects
then we will work out what kinds of
decision-making structures
work best for that that scenario the
other thing is we're pretty aware of the
kind of
natural human tendency to create
bureaucracies
like it's something we are contending
with in our group calls anyway with the
demand
to create rules and we're very resistant
to that so
in that sense yeah i think i think we're
good at that
we'll just keep doing what we're doing i
think it's working um but there will be
times where there's kind of a
disagreement so i think what we might
end up doing
is is having between uv and i uh
slightly higher amount of voting shares
so that we can swing it if there's a
stalemate we can swing it in either
direction and we're pretty good with
decision making like
we can make fast decisions and if it's
really split down the middle then
fine we'll break the tie
i just had this vision of like it
becoming jersey shore with the
documentary series and then the
disagreements are like amplified
drawings yeah i'm yeah
i pay a lot of attention the story
telling my parents like we're
since we've come back to canada we're
staying with my parents so they
you know hgtv is on all the time
upstairs and i i mean
they're watching like homesteading
channels and stuff like that and
i always watch these shows and think i
hate the manufactured drama that they
insert into all of these shows i would
really not want to do that so
let's have real conversations recorded
let's not try and you know make it more
entertaining for entertainment's sake
and i'm sure there will be lots of
failures and hilarious situations to
make it entertaining like you know have
you guys seen the biggest little farm
that's a good good show yeah
yeah if you needed like a rowdy stoic to
guest appear i'll happily come on and
cost some drama for you guys
definitely sounds good yeah
yeah we don't shy away from the conflict
as as is part of the stoic
philosophy so we're in it yeah
all right so um drew
uh buck miller and i have to
i gave everyone permission unmute
themselves so you have to unmute
yourself again mike
true can you so i had a question
you were emphasizing the not
removing too far from you know not
escapism and you mentioned you know
bringing people in who have an
entrepreneurial spirit what i'm
wondering about is you know with
a lot of we're going remote now what
does it look like
um you know say if someone were to come
from the u.s
and work are you looking mainly for
people who are self-employed or
um what does it look like if someone's
working remote from
from a company based you know i live
actually like just south of you in
in idaho um it's like what would that
look like
across the borders i'm not familiar with
the like how taxes work or
um if that's an issue well we've done
the digital nomad thing for a lot of
years so
we kind of know our way around that and
i think
you know one thing we one situation we
don't want to have is for people's
income to be completely dependent on us
on the property and on the business um
just because that sets up some pretty
gross dynamics over time where it's like
there there's kind of a
super dependency that that i don't know
is unhealthy
yeah we've been there before too and
it's it's really not healthy mm-hmm
yeah so as far as immigration and that
kind of thing um we expect people to
figure that out on their own
like we we generally are looking for
people who are pretty
uh self-sufficient self-starters you
know can can figure things out
um so we do have some americans that are
planning to come
and they are navigating that process
by themselves um but for the most
yeah and actually one brit so
yeah you know what actually he's here um
uh daniel if you want to pipe up with
any of your progress with that you can
but
you also kind of make it obvious to me
now that we need to have like a resource
page or something for immigration
um but yeah as far as the
self-employment goes
i mean you can be on a tourist visa for
a good
length of time and i think you by
default get a six-month visa if you're
an american coming into
canada something along those lines so
six months out of the year i think yeah
it's permitted so there's there there is
a way to do that
at the beginning as far as like super
long-term permanent stay that's
something you got to figure out
but i think yeah that's something we
should do is put up an immigration
page somewhere yeah and right now with
covid
um borders are closed so unless
yeah people coming in from other
countries would have to have a good
precedent to be here
in the eyes of immigration anyway yeah
cool louise you had a question
hi yeah i was wondering uh what the
capital requirements or budget will be
anticipated to build all the common
space projects you propose in the video
ranging from
the event center to the new dwellings to
maker's
space to the road well a fortunate
benefit of the documentary is that
there's a lot of
and the podcast and the events and
everything that we're doing is there's a
lot of space
for um sponsorship so
what and we've we've got a lot of
experience with sponsorships as well so
i anticipate
that a lot of the maker space will be
funded through sponsorships and
donations
and we actually have a partner already
on the team who does that who kind of
travels around and sets up maker spaces
and innovation centers he's already done
one
in caslow so he knows how to do that so
we're probably going to use him as a
resource
for that then when it comes to the
individual properties well maybe you
want to take that
yeah so we're currently in negotiations
with several companies that do
building prefab construction and that
sort of thing
so we will have more information about
the specific costs
soon um as far as what we're
looking to raise to start is 2 million
canadian and that's to acquire the
property and do some updates
but that's not to build build out
everything that's in the video that will
probably be over several years and will
require more funding and we can't
give a specific number of how much that
will cost well our priority in the first
year
is definitely at least four new uh
dwellings for just couples um so
probably not ideal for families but
you know you would get like a single
kind of geodesic dome or something that
you could
move into and stay on um we're looking
at prefab
houses cabins geodesic domes tiny homes
like different options
the other thing that's worth mentioning
is the existing owners of the property
uh own and or they operate uh a
timber framing company so they make
timber frame homes
and they have typically
shipped them across throughout the
states and canada
but they their mill is less than five
minutes drive
away from the property um and they've
already got a lot of experience building
they've um
on the property they've built a number
of structures on the property already so
they're going to be a great resource for
us for building and for keeping the
costs down
and that also keeps it local you know it
solves a lot of the supply chain issues
that a lot of companies have seen with
covid because all the materials are
local
labor is local but even with like the
geodesic domes
there's so much opportunity for
sponsorships because suddenly
you know if we have a variety of
different types of dwellings they become
the showroom
for these companies to use they can send
their people there they can be included
in the documentary
series like there's a lot of exposure
that they get for just donating those
materials to us so yeah we're looking to
leverage a lot of different partnerships
to make this happen
yeah and then to tag on a question
uh i was wondering what the current
infrastructure is for that
like plot of land like internet fiber
electricity water phone all those sort
of
like modern um
yeah so it's it's been run as a organic
farm since the 90s at least
it already has three houses on it which
are fully functional and fully renovated
uh it has a bunch of barns and different
structures for animals you know fencing
it has three wells and three septic
tanks one for each house
it's uh it has a grid connection but it
also has two bays of solar panels
so it's uh it produces its own energy
and then it doesn't have batteries so at
night
it will buy energy back from the grid
and it ends up being that they basically
pay very little at all if at all for
energy
over the year so um and we we
will probably look at at getting
batteries so that we can be completely
off-grid optional
um but yeah it's already set up fully
and fully functional
as far as internet it currently has a
dish
internet um and we've talked to the
local internet company about
getting fiber and it'll um it's about i
think five kilometers away
is the connection so we just need to
string the cable those five kilometers
and it'll just cost us but that's within
the budget
is uh jm in in the call right now
can you unmute yourself if you are
okay guess not well he would have more
specific information
yeah thanks
thanks louise um
[Music]
albert you had a question
yeah hey mike and uv um so you know i'm
sure
uh starting off you guys are gonna be
utilizing fiat the fund
and like when you get your village
running you're gonna you guys could be
using you know canadian dollars or
whatnot
but i was wondering if you had any
thoughts on eventually issuing your own
digital currency or utilizing crypto or
blockchain technology
yes love that idea we've had so many
people ask us that
i've i've made a coin of my own just
for fun that's out there on the
blockchain don't go looking for it
really not a good investment um but yeah
we thought about that because of the
flexibility
and the programmability of uh using a
cryptocurrency on the property we've
also
i mean i know that a lot of
civilizations in the past and
communities in the past have
eventually created their own currency
the with the technology that we have
access to now there's a huge amount of
flexibility so i'm excited about that
idea but is it a necessity for the first
year or two
no um but i i love the idea of
everything having
of having an economy inside of the
village and in
to that like to an extent
the entire region of the kootenays i
think that'd be really cool
i think for for the network aspect that
would be really great um to have
some sort of a token that is used across
these types of villages all over the
world
yeah where you know people can trade
accommodations kind of have programs
where you go visit each other and learn
things or
use each other's services yeah there's
definitely opportunity for that it'll
just be
sometime down the road if anyone here
has expertise on that actually that
would be great reach out to me privately
we'll chat very cool
okay um anna you had a question
you can unmute yourself
there you go oh we're playing mute tag
there you go
hi um i'm fascinated with the idea
and at the same time i'm aware of so
many other experiments
in this field um
so i'm very interested in how do you
differ
also the villages in italy
which are empty and they are very
beautiful
so so why not take over a village
already existing
well we we're not trying to be the only
one out there we're not trying to create
competitive dynamics against other smart
villages
so we had i mean we spent four or five
years in bulgaria
and have traveled around europe quite
extensively so we know about those
abandoned villages all over the world
well i'm bulgarian by the way
oh oh great yeah so
nasty we
we decided that we would like to set
this up in our home country where our
family lives
but i think that people in different
countries
around the world can use the different
available
you know infrastructure and and land and
zoning and whatever that suits to each
region and i think that's the beauty of
it you know there's some
sort of different opportunities in every
area that people should be utilizing
bulgaria has a huge advantage i mean
they have entire villages that are
completely abandoned and
people are saying in italy exactly
um and i mean you can get your hands on
property on on an existing structure for
only a couple of thousand dollars so
it's uh it's attractive and there's lots
of opportunity all over the world for
this
type of thing yeah we're kind of taking
a difficult route because canada is a
little more expensive and we're
so mobile we could do this in mexico or
we could do it in bulgaria or something
but
um it needs to be feasible anywhere
i think this is like this is a a new way
that human civilization could live
and so we're you know i recognize that
there are some things that we're doing
that are not exactly
replicable for other people you know not
everyone has a podcast that they can
offer sponsorship on
and get a bunch of free stuff so and not
everyone
might have the ability to crowdfund
something like this
but a lot of families do have the
ability to
put their connections together pool
their resources and then buy it by at
least some
level of acreage acreage and do
something like this themselves so
there's lots of little bits and pieces
that you can
do yourself and that's what we hope to
inspire people to do
as far as what we're doing that's
different uh well we're integrating
technology
that's one of the things that's
definitely different
um some of the ecovillages that we've
looked at
uh are trying to run away from
technology
we don't see technology as evil or you
know
bad somehow we want to integrate it just
in a way that
technology should be serving human
nature
and the bioregion and be out of the way
yeah yeah
what else are we doing that's different
well we're integrating a lot of
different
aspects like the self personal
development is really big for us
and we are very developmentally focused
rather than trying
to um present some sort of an ideology
or some sort of perfect way of living
that people need to follow
or you know institute some sort of a
religion or utopia
or you know specific political structure
we're very experimental
um we're kind of agnostic in that sense
we just want to
try different stuff and see what works i
kind of like the idea of the burgundy
robes that we might just do that but
yeah it's a it's been a running joke
because everyone thinks we're making a
commune or a cult or something
not everyone but once in a while we we
do get people like oh so is this a
religious thing or is it a commune
it's just like you know people have
their own associations that they they
come up with based on what they've seen
and so we've just started joking around
with these purple robes like you know
the when you come and visit in the in
the visiting suite we'll have the
bathrobes be purple
just as an inside joke cool
um emily hi
um exciting to be here and hear about
all of this
um my question is around
like initial investment like are you
like if i wanted to come up there and
join would i be renting a space or
are you gonna open it up for people
buying land
are they gonna buy land are they just
gonna buy a structure like what's
yeah what's your legally the the
path that's the most straightforward is
to be looking for loans from our
community to be able to buy the property
and then there will be multiple
different types of businesses
on the structure and hopefully people
who come to move there will also
start their own businesses um so there
are going to be different
investment opportunities in the future
that said if people are loaning us
money there are a lot of perks that
we're kind of bringing into that like
if you want to rent or stay on the
property or lease something for an
extended period of time you would get a
discount
if you're one of the original lenders
and first priority because there's
actually been
kind of an overwhelming demand for um
first stays
at the property yeah short especially
long term stays
so we're trying to figure out how to
manage that and how to prioritize
um yeah how to give those perks to the
people that help us fund the initial
round
it's also a good filter mechanism too to
do the loaning
instead of the initial investor like to
give equity away
for the company that owns the land so
quickly
because we're going to be living near
each other all the time so we need to
make sure there's a
functional you know it's not that we're
looking for a certain culture or a
certain type of person we want diversity
of ideas but
how good are people at conflict
resolution
like i want to i want to learn that
about people very quickly um
and that yeah how good are they at
collaborating
yeah and these are things that are very
hard to each other teach i think and and
not necessarily
a priority for us to like build people
up from scratch like there's definitely
something you can come into this with
the set of skills and abilities that
will prioritize yeah
so the it would be a loan the way it's
working with some people
is that they're loaning a larger chunk
of money and then we're figuring out
what
the equity would look like in the future
so
a portion of that loan would convert
into
uh equity in the company that owns the
land which is kind of
similar to like a community land trust
except it's owned by a company
yeah it's a more simple version of it
because we've looked at doing a
community land trust and talked to some
people who've
actually successfully set it up it's a
very lengthy process a lot of red tape
and you know we have a friend who spent
half a million dollars on lawyer fees
and several years just to set up this
like
co-op ownership structure so it's within
the current system it's quite a
nightmare
so we're looking at simpler structures
that kind of carry the same purpose
yeah so a company that would own that
would have
would own the assets own the land and
the
has one singular business focus which is
essentially like
renting and leasing the property or be
almost like a real estate developer
which is something we're exploring so
that seems to me just to be the easiest
route
so essentially people would be able to
forgive a portion of their loan in the
future
if the rest of the community agrees
um be able to convert a portion of that
into equity
so my just a quick follow-up question
like my
my my approach would be i would want to
come up and stay
for a chunk of time and field
out the land and you know i live in
santa cruz right now so this is also
like a jump in latitude
um but yeah so to so
when are you guys opening it up for
uh people to come and stay for months or
how yeah how is that if you're
uh well we're we're planning on doing
renovations we want to be
living there by about the end of october
or november so we're going to spend the
winter there
we're going to be doing renovations on
the big house and
actually pretty much all of these
structures there and
hopefully setting up new structures for
visitors
making some space for rvs to park
because a lot of people have expressed
interest in coming up in an rv and
staying here for a while
so uh that will be a priority creating
some structures
and spaces so that people can come and
visit for shorter periods of time to
feel it out and get to know everyone and
see
if it's a good fit for them and the
initial lenders really there's one
couple that wants is is we're talking
with right now about the loan structure
in the equity structure and they
want to come as soon as possible and are
totally happy to be living there through
the winter so
there is space i mean we have we
definitely have the space for that
awesome thank you thanks
david chilcott you had a bunch of
questions if you can ask
one of them
um so i'm most interested
in kind of um
what you've just been talking about uh
kind of about the equity
slash loan slash business structures
um and the relationship to
ownership equity and decision making
um it's not really a well-formed
question but i'd love to hear
a little more about how
the formal and the informal structures
align
um other than what we've already said
we're still working out the details
because uh a big part of this is
kind of letting it emerge in a way that
makes sense
for the people that are co-creating it
with us so
rather than having this like we've got
it all figured out and we've got this
perfect top-down structure that
everybody plugs into
we're see we're saying it like no like
the people who are coming and
co-creating it with us
who are going to be stakeholders why
don't we just figure out what works
between us like as as humans as a
relationship
and so it's been working out well so far
we've learned a lot and figured out a
lot of the questions that we
that were kind of unclear or that we
were thinking about differently before
and after talking to people we realized
actually oh it's going to be better to
do it this way
so it's really a changing it's a living
thing
it's not a static thing so yeah what
we've said so far is our current way of
thinking as it evolves more and as we
you know put things into contracts then
we will you know put out some updates in
the future but
for now this is where we're where we're
at yeah
that makes good sense to me the idea
that um
rather than have policies or rules as a
substitute for conversation that you get
skillful
at having meaningful and
authentic conversation yeah
um one of the things that we've been
doing recently so um we have an online
community
and uh in our online community this
month we have a theme
of indigenous wisdom so we've been
reading a bunch of books and having a
bunch of conversations
and doing podcast episodes around that
theme and um
you know just kind of noticing the
differences between the
indigenous mindset and the western
mindset western mindset is
hyperstructured like everything has to
be figured out and everything has to be
based on rules
and people because they are so reliant
on rules they actually end up being
really out of touch with reality with
what's actually happening now
in this moment with these people you
know
and what's emerging um and so we want to
bring
bring back that more of that connected
mindset of what is actually emerging
what's happening like what are the
opportunities and possibilities here
how are things changing just as a result
of us
talking here so it's um
yeah it's it's kind of counterintuitive
sometimes to people but
once they get into it they realize that
it's it
really works and it's something that
doesn't scale
which is probably why corporations and
you know these big institutions don't
use it because it is really reliant on
the relationship between two or three or
you know a small group of people
um but in those kinds of configurations
i think it works
really well and the the more people do
it the more skillful they get at it
yeah dunbar's number about 120-ish
the number of folks you can actually
have connected
relationship with yeah and and this is
why
um the earlier question was like how
many people are you gonna have living
there this is why we want to cap it at
50 adults
so that means that there's going to be
several children and several neighbors
that you have
you know close relationships with but
there are some books that have been
written by people who've
set up co-housing communities you know
for decades
all over the world and that's the number
that they came up with 40 to 50 adults
is the max that you want to have in a
co-housing community
if you get over that then it starts
breaking down and there's just too many
um kind of clashing expectations and
it's hard to come to consensus
yeah thank you yeah
thanks david um i'll follow up with that
uh you know how the drummer breaky talks
about ecology of practices and all these
like here at the store we have a wisdom
gym where we're developing that
and you guys have a course rebel wisdom
has it was there any kind of like
um monastic academy everybody daniel
thornton is a great
example he has circling embedded in
their ecology
um are you guys going to have something
like that available for the community
mm-hmm yeah and what would be in it
like would be circling would it be
meditation
classes you have like something fixed or
you're waiting to see what emerges
we already do uh some version of
circling every thursday like it's kind
of that same like
that same check-in procedure that you do
with circling
um checking with yourself checking with
the room um
but the subject is not generally
constrained to any arena it goes
wherever it goes wherever we feel like
bringing it and we might talk about
external events and stuff but we've got
a lot of practice doing that
would love to bring that into the
physical space
it's basically a form of collective
intelligence
yeah and it only works in a small group
i think 15 is the most
number of people that you you can have
until you start
to break the coherence to me they're
basically two
really important schools of thought and
personal development
it's it's the interpersonal
interrelational aspect and then the
solo you know in silent darkness in your
room
kind of work like that meditative or
psychedelics
root um so
those two things we have quite a lot of
experience with
um more so the collective aspect in the
last couple of years but
we've we used to have a meditation app
we uv teaches meditation every monday
like
that's a big part of our what we do
already
so bringing that into the physical space
is pretty natural and easy
and we plan to invite a lot of other
facilitators as well
because um you know i think that it's
it's important to have
different modalities and different
perspectives so that it doesn't get
centralized
um so and there's already been a lot of
interest
you know from from the people that we've
previously interviewed on the podcast
and just people from my
network who've come up and put up their
hand and said hey i facilitate this sort
of practice or this sort of thing i'd
love to be part of this
yeah yeah very cool
um so we have about 10 minutes left i'm
curious how long that
video is like the one with the ariel
do you want to pivot to that sooner sure
yeah it is
four minutes long wow that's almost the
exact same length as the other video
yeah four minutes
so maybe we'll feel one more question um
or how about a statement uh christian
you had a statement about the
interpersonal aspect
would you want to unmute yourself and
yeah sure um i just wanted to say it
feels like the interpersonal aspects
will be imported considering that the
city
itself is already hyper individualized
so it kind of goes back to like peter's
questions like what are some specific
things you've been working on but i feel
like you guys already touched upon that
but
how is that like aspect really important
to you guys
yeah i actually want to expand
into something that we haven't talked
about yet from that question
um so my vision for the long term of
this place
is to have basically a school
so i've been thinking a lot about how
children are raised and how we're
educated
you know how we're basically programmed
by society
and i think that it's not optimal for
the kind of world that we're going into
you know it was
suitable for a more stable society for a
more stable climate but now that things
are becoming more chaotic and things are
changing very quickly
i think people need to be more adaptive
and more responsive
so we need to change our parenting
practices and our education practices
to to fit that so that you know our
children and adults can thrive in this
new world that we're going into
so that's my vision for the long term
like for the next you know 20 years or
something
is um setting up a school and the way
that i see this
is like how do we make regenerative
humans
you know we the in the past people have
talked about sustainability
as kind of the you know the green
approach to how we relate to the
environment
but i don't think that's enough because
sustainability means
that we are uh maintaining something
and maybe we're maintaining things that
are not optimal
so regenerative means restoring
ecosystems to health
so you are an ecosystem too you as an
individual like you are
a collection of organs and different
systems that work together
and then communities and and all the
interrelationships in those communities
is also an ecosystem and then there's
the broader ecosystem
of the bioregion you know the plants and
animals and natural cycles in that
system
and so the the relationships between
those
macro and microsystems are really
important and the relationships within
them are also extremely important
so the health of those relationships is
is what makes the whole thing run
so i think that interrelational dynamics
are absolutely at the core
of all of this and not just between
humans but also
in how we relate to ourselves and how we
relate to all the living beings in the
bioregion
so to be more specific um
i think a lot of it is emergent a lot of
it
is is in the moment while you're
relating to each different
living thing or system you're figuring
out how to do it optimally i don't think
it's a top-down thing
so it's a lot of practice basically
yeah i hope that answers it and i hope
it's not too
nebulous cool so i'll ask the last
question and maybe we can pivot to the
video
and a lot of people are dropping so we
didn't get to all the questions so i'm
sorry um but a lot of people are
dropping advice too in the chat so
if you want to change uh save the chat
before you guys leave you can do that i
believe
um or i can send it to you after the the
fact
so the question i had is it's pretty
simple um
what is your uh greatest concerns about
this project things you're most worried
about
and what are the things you're most
excited about
great question yeah i i would think
government interference
um we want you know we if here's an
example we're
doing this tesla car sharing program
because we partnered with another
company who already has a fleet of
teslas and we were thinking like what
does it cost to actually get one so i
looked into buying one
and i found out like the canadian
government taxes
these sustainable cars with about 12 000
on each purchase so you know there's a
lot of lip service when it comes to
government intervention and
and acceptance and help that i think is
not reflective in the taxes
and not a reflective in how they
actually support programs
and i think if we got in the way of any
type of like big
business we could face some
[Music]
resistance on the other hand we are
in talks with the local government i
mean this is a very
small town um it's not a big city so i
think
um there will be a lot more opportunity
to innovate
and work with the local government and
actually be able to
adjust the regulations to make this
thing possible and so far it's been you
know the reception of our project has
been very positive
and so there's actually an another eco
village on vancouver island called ours
our eco village or ours eco village um
and that
they've been doing this for a couple
decades and they've worked with the
local government
to actually change um some of the
regulations to enable that project
because
they have had a very positive effect on
the community so the government sees it
as a good thing
so i hope to do the same you know to
establish relationships with the local
structures to make it possible
um as far as what am i most afraid of
uh or most challenged by
you know this is funny but the the
perception of what we're doing
matters because when people come
with a preconceived notion of what this
is
it changes how they interact again you
know it changes that relationship
dynamic
so we've definitely had some funny
reactions mostly positive but a few
funny ones um and so i see that as an
ongoing challenge that how do we
storytell
in a way that accurately describes what
we're doing
and and helps people to understand
uh where they fit in in what we're doing
and how it affects them
so that's part of the reason why we want
to do this documentary
so that we can you know transparently
show what we're doing
and that's part of the reason why we
want to create templates
and document processes for how we're
doing things so that we can show people
ah yeah this is how it's structured
and you know you can you can learn from
this you can take it or even just like
if people
are not interested in setting it up
themselves they can see how we do things
and why we do things in a certain way
so yeah a lot of transparency and uh
also inviting people to come out and
stay i mean that's going to be a
priority holding a lot of events so that
people can just come and see it for
themselves
that it's not a closed community or you
know sex called
sex cult the meta-modern
wild wild country that's associated yeah
cool um so yeah we have about four
minutes left wanna
watch the sure there's no audio here so
we can continue to
answer questions um because this video
doesn't have audio
let's go road trip yep we're on we will
so yeah you'll recognize a bunch of
these shots but
um there's a lot of new ones here as
well
so yeah any other questions we can keep
going here all right
we can talk about what we're seeing as
well yeah i'm curious
what like kind of i play by play maybe
can you see my mouse
uh it's hidden in the corner now
oh yeah i see your mouse a little bit
okay so along the top here
is the dividing line of the property
we're facing south now we're facing
north
um so there's a southern property that's
bigger than the current one
than this one that we're looking at
potentially acquiring in the future if
funding permits you can see there's a
lot of farmland
it's um mostly surrounded by crown land
which means government on land so it's
just forest
um it's just at the edge of a town
about five kilometers out of town this
is the five bedroom house these are the
solar panels here there's a there's a
kennel for dogs
uh there's like kinds of stuff for
having animals and stuff they used to be
well known in the region for being deer
farmers they had hundreds of deer
um on the property and then at different
times had
horses and cows and pigs and all kinds
of different animals
so yeah the current owners have a lot of
experience in farming which is cool
yeah um there's yeah so
this is there's a bunch of vegetables
being grown there right now
organic and this is the
the river where um there's
a small stream that runs from the river
um so we have
access to the water from that stream as
well for irrigation
and there are also several wells on the
property the property actually extends
up
along this line above the ridge so it's
not all flat a good portion of it is
also this forested area
about 40 of it actually is that forested
area and that's probably that portion is
unzoned
so it's probably where we're going to
start building some of the structures
this is on that side this is one of the
two bedroom houses
and then there is this path that
connects
the two-bedroom house to the second
two-bedroom house and along this path is
where we're thinking of building a lot
of the different structures
the dome the four domes that we start at
the beginning or tiny homes or cabins
yeah and so it's quite a lot of space um
and then up here is the path leading to
what's currently being used as an airbnb
this is a two bedroom house here
there's water like there's wells and
storage areas and all kinds of stuff
there yeah so
the fact that part of the property is
unzoned is very handy because it means
there are fewer limitations on what we
can build and how many structures we can
build
um yeah the other side of the property
is zoned agricultural so it does have
limitations but
we are going to work with the local
government to change the zoning so that
we can
um have more structures um among the
farmland as well
it's beautiful yeah it is yeah
yeah it's it's really nice um it's about
two hours from the local airport it's
about an hour and a half from nelson
which is the nearest city
um five minute last
five minute walk even to the nearest gas
station
not quite a five minute walk but yeah
like five minute drive
um tons of kind of uh nature activities
there's a white rock
rafting company nearby uh and we're
surrounded by crown land for quite a
long
ways going up north yeah there's a lot
of places for hiking and
dirt biking and stuff if you're into
that yeah there are two national parks
just
literally you know in the backyard um
there's a it's it's the
uh world center for cat skiing
i think it's where cat scheme was
invented so it's this kind of tractor
thing that drives up the mountain
and then people ski from there um
yeah so there's quite a lot of winter
activities as well i think sometime
either this year or next year there's
going to be a big
kind of electric vehicle conference
happening that one of
our partners is helping to organize
so there'll be all types of different
electric vehicles there
atvs dirt bikes boats e-boats is one
thing we're really excited about having
in this region because
the a lot of the lakes connect in a
network
so there's a lot of uh terrain to
explore
through boating yeah and uh
there's yeah so caslo is an interesting
town this in
closest town there's a lot of young kind
of entrepreneurial people living there
so
for how small it is there's a lot of
innovation happening
um there's a new innovation center that
just opened there
and nelson obviously is a cultural uh
center in the region where there's a lot
of
arts and festivals and things like that
happening
i just clicked replay here so we can
stop anytime
so yeah we passed the the hour so we
probably should
close out um any uh
yeah any kind of closing thoughts for um
us here today
yeah um so we're doing a a kind of a
social event tonight
um that tyson is going to be hosting um
this relates to the indigenous wisdom
and we'll do breakout rooms and stuff so
we'll be there tonight at
six o'clock 6 00 p.m pacific which will
be nine eastern
yeah and where can they find out about
that um
tyson tyson can you post can you post
the zoom
registration link in the chat yeah one
moment thank you
oh jm is here now okay hi jim hi
sorry i was in and out of meetings it's
good to see you guys
you came up quite a number of times ah
here i am
connect with me on linkedin everyone
i'll post my link
yeah so calls to action here um check
out the page futurethinkers.org
village um tyson's going to post the
link for the event tonight i think
that's kind of it if you want to ask us
more
questions uh we'll be in there tonight
maybe we can hang out a little later
um we're going to be uh maybe that's not
what we're saying
mm-hmm yeah i think that's it yeah we're
um
we're still in the middle of our uh
fundraising
but we've got more than half pledged
already
so it's it's going quite well but if
this is something that you're interested
in contributing to then get in touch
great and i put the links and then the
show notes are not showing us the chat
right now
yeah cool thank you for hosting us this
is awesome
we love what you're doing here so yeah
great to be a part of it
yeah i'll make some uh closing
announcements for the snow in a moment
but mike yubi
thanks so much for coming to stowa if
you ever need the star or me to help you
with this project
you know for whatever reason uh just
reach out i'll be happy to help i'm
really uh supportive of what you guys
doing
awesome thank you so uh some upcoming
announcements um at the store uh we're
actually doing something uh
kind of kind of relevant to what was
just spoken about we're doing uh
empathy circle training i don't know if
anyone can see that um so edwin roche
does these empathy circles
uh to kind of create like your listening
muscle greater empathy we're having uh
the medic mediation campfire on sundays
at 3 30 pm eastern time
throughout october we're doing the
training there so if you're interested
in that you can use rcp to the
that which would be pretty cool excited
for
that now we can trade notes on on how
this stuff goes uh mike and uv as well
um and at 8 p.m eastern time uh
so looks like our events are not going
to
cross each other we got another event
coming up in an hour glimpses of
communitas
with donna rodriguez which is another
sort of we space kind of uh
collective presencing type thing you can
rsv there
um and if you we have tons of events at
the stawa
check it out stor.ca if you like to
support us on patreon you can do that as
well
so again mike uv everyone thank you so
much for coming to the store today
[Music]
and like if you if you want to save the
chats you can you can just click
on the little dots and you can see that
a lot of people are dropping some
goodies
oh yeah one more thing i forgot actually
everyone's leaving well if you want to
go
join our community uh go to
futurethinkers.org friend and you'll get
two months off we charge just because
we have facilitators uh helping us
organize the content and stuff but it's
five bucks a month usually
if you want to check it out for two
months then follow that link
but did you give the link
teacherthinker.org friend
yeah that gives two months free cool
right bye everyone bye